MELANIE DUBBERLEY

MellieDeeDevelops@outlook.com | 916-596-0496 | Sacramento, CA 95835 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/melaniedubbs | GitHub: www.github.com/MellieDee Portfolio: www.melliedee.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with background in creativity and science. Experienced self-starter thrives in quick-moving companies where practical food industry experience and collaboration are valued. Freelance food stylist career consisted of developing, testing, revising, finalizing, and ultimately styling the recipes, a process which directly translates to coding. Maintains the big picture while working independently or on a team. Honest communication between and having fun with team members is the best way to get the job done.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Experience including but not limited to HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node, MySQL/Mongo DB	s, React.js, Mobile-First Design
PROJECTS	
Regex Tutorial: Format Dates to ISO8601 https://gist.github.com/MellieDee/28442f71 Description: Introduction to common concepts by examining the syntax fo	
 Walk 'n Spot https://walk-n-spot.herokuapp.com https://github.com/MellieDee/Wall □ Description: An interactive web app for hikers to find animals on trails in a search Role: Team of five. Responsible for initial result cards code. Drafted code for since Continuously communicated with all team members. Authored presentation in Tech Used: JavaScript, Node, Express with Sessions, MySQL, Sequelize 	ched city. Izing of search boxes.
README Generator https://github.com/MellieDee/readMe-generator https://youtu.b □ Description: CLI app to generate a quality README.md which includes a screen Read Reading Release. □ Role: Developer. Determine final style of and coded JS to generate README, indeployment URL, screenshot and licensing information as a badge. □ Tech Used: JavaScript, Node, npm, Inquirer	enshot of the user's app.
 deCrypto https://github.com/MellieDee/deCrypto https://melliedee.github.io/deCrypto Description: Resource to demystify cryptocurrency. Upon start, presents top 5 cryptocurrencies at a given moment. Users can calculate buying power or learn basic information through About, FAQ's or Glossary. Role: Team of three. Defacto Team lead. Sourced APIs and wrote JS for API calls. Worked closely with teammate who wrote general JS. Brainstormed user-interface ideas and implemented with teammate who wrote style code. Authored web copy for About, FAQs and Glossary modals. Tech Used: HTML, Tailwind, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs 	
EXPERIENCE	
Co-Owner/CEO/ Lead Crepista Farmland Street, LLC., Crepes & Pies, Food Truck	Oct. 2017 – June 2019 Woodland, CA
Set sales goals by maintaining electronic accounting records and generating fir Innovated food truck cuisine by developing non-traditional hand-held, savory at Integrated new and seasonal menu items quarterly that met cost specifications Built community ties by catering local events monthly. Advanced marketing plan by uploading pictures of recipes, ingredients and pro-	nancial reports quarterly. nd sweet, crepes and pies. s.

platforms.

Owner/President/Freelance Food Consultant Nov. 2001 - Dec. 2016 As Food Fashions, LLC. Rahwav, NJ ☐ Visualized clients' two-dimensional storyboards; then engineered and built three-dimensional scaffolds to support food on set for photographers thereby bringing their storyboards to life. ☐ Evaluated sensory and functional attributes of foods to determine the best recipe. ☐ Styled a range of foods for a variety of clients by managing multiple deadlines simultaneously. ☐ Cultivated client relationships lasting over 15 years by providing creative and dependable service. ☐ Understood client's broad view by collaborating with packaging, creative and marketing departments. Procurement Specialist Dec. 2015 - Dec 2016 Farm Fresh To You West Sacramento, CA ☐ Reinvigorated weekly menus by acquiring unique local or organic, farm and handmade items. ☐ Increased the number of available value-added skus overall approximately by 25%.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University California, Davis, CA

6-month intensive curriculum delivering practical coding skills including but not limited to experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, MongoDb, Express, React, Node, Agile development, and GitHub use.

□ Maintained weekly desired return on investment by balancing type and cost of items offered for sale.
 □ Analyzed key performance indicators using Microsoft Excel for weekly sales reports to management.

Associate in Occupational Studies, Culinary Art: Culinary Institute of America, Hyde Park, NY Schieffelin Award for Scholastic Achievement in Hospitality Management

Concurrent Bachelor of Science, Food Biochemistry: University of California, Davis, CA Graduated with honors. Fmil Mrak Prize

Concurrent Bachelor of Arts, Art Studio: University of California, Davis, CA Graduated with honors.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Certificate: Understanding Financial Statements: Company Position, University of Illinois, at Urbana-Champaign, IL, Coursera, August 2021

Certificate: The Importance of Listening, Northwestern University, IL, Coursera, June 2016

Certificate: What is Social? Northwestern University, IL, Coursera, November 2015

Certificate: Marketing in a Digital World, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL, Coursera, October 2015

Statement: Inspiring Leadership through Emotional Intelligence, Case Western Reserve University, OH, Coursera, October 2015

Speaker: International Association of Culinary Professionals, Washington D.C. 2015 "How to Make Chocolate Look as Good as It Tastes," Annual Conference, Intensive Session